Finding Aid for Fred W. Green papers, 1881-1939
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Fred W. Green papers 1881-1939
Green, Fred W. (Fred Warren), 1872-1936.
851410 Aa 2; AC; Ac
Republican Governor of Michigan, 1927-1930, from Ionia. Correspondence and other papers, 1898-1936, concerning the Spanish-American War, Republican politics, and personal affairs; and scrapbooks, 1896-1929, covering his political career and election campaigns; and photographs.
2.5 linear feet in 3 boxes
4 oversize volumes
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. Fred W. Green (donor no. 1098 ) and came to the library in 1940.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Fred Warren Green was born Oct. 20, 1872, in Manistee, Michigan. He graduated from the Law School of the University of Michigan in 1898, then served in the Spanish-American War, commanding Company G, 31st Michigan Volunteer Infantry in Cuba. After the war, he practiced law in Ypsilanti, also becoming owner of a furniture company. In the 1920s he moved his law practice and business affairs to Ionia, Michigan.
Politically active, Green served as mayor of Ionia, was treasurer of the Republican State Central Committee for 10 years, and was a delegate to several national conventions. In 1926, he defeated the incumbent Alexander Groesbeck to win the Republican gubernatorial nomination. In the general election he defeated Democrat William Comstock. He won re-elected in 1928, but did not seek a third term in 1930. He died Nov. 30, 1936.
The Fred W. Green collection is comprised of correspondence, scrapbooks, speeches, photographs, postcards, and miscellaneous other materials. Some of the correspondence covers the period when Green was at Santa Clara, Cuba in 1899, but the bulk of the letters fall within the period of his gubernatorial service.
Subjects:
Depressions--1929--Michigan.; Elections--Michigan--1926.; Elections--Michigan--1936.; Furniture industry and trade--Michigan--Ionia.; Green, Fred W. (Fred Warren), 1872-1936.; Ionia (Mich.); Michigan. Civil Service Study Commission.; Michigan--Politics and government--1922-1928.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Politicians--Michigan.; Republican Party (Mich.); United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 31st (1898-1899); Ypsilanti-Reed Furniture Company (Ionia, Mich.); Spanish-American War, 1898.; Governors--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Carriages and coaches.; Clothing and dress--1921-1930.; Donkeys.; Michigan State Normal College--Football.; Elephants.; Golf.; Green, Fred W. (Fred Warren), 1872-1936.; Green family.; Horses.; Mackinac Island (Mich.); Parachuting.; Political elections--1926.; Politics and government--1922-1928.; Politics and government--1929-1938.; Symbols.; Governors--Michigan.
Contributors:
Abbott, Horatio J. (Horatio Johnson), 1876-1936; Bridges, Styles, 1898-1961.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Crawford, Fred L., 1888-1957.; Dempsey, Jack, 1895-1983.; Ferguson, Homer, 1889-1982.; Fitzgerald, Frank Dwight, 1885-1939.; Guest, Edgar A. (Edgar Albert), 1881-1959.; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.; Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961.; Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Musselwhite, Harry Webster, 1868-1955.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Pollock, James K. (James Kerr), 1898-1968; Potter, William W., 1869-1940.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Van Wagoner, Murray Delos, 1898-; Yost, Fielding Harris, 1871-1946.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Correspondence and other papers
  - 1898-June 1936, 32 folders (Box 1)
  - July 1936-1939, 7 folders (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Governors' Conference 1927, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Speeches, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Programs, invitations, memorabilia, 3 folders (Box 2)
    (also in oversize folder Ac)
  - Peggy Green journal 1921 (Box 2)
  - Photographs: portraits; photographs relating to Green's gubernatorial campaign and his career; clipping photo of Michigan State Normal College football team, circa 1895 (Box 2)
    (also oversize folder Ac)
  - Postcards (Box 2)
  - Volume containing election tickets and returns 1881-1903 (Box 2)
- Scrapbooks /clippings
  - Loose clippings 1898-1936, undated, 10 folders (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1919-1920 (state politics and government) (Volume 1)
    - 1926 (politics and campaign for governor) (Volume 2)
    - 1926, 1929 (politics and campaign for governor) (Volume 3)
    - Campaign art 1896 (clippings of caricatures of political figures) (Volume 4)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Abbott, Horatio J. (Horatio Johnson), 1876-
Oct. 1926; April-June 1935
Bridges, Styles, 1898-1961.
Feb.-Mar. 1936
Couzens, James, 1872-1936.
Apr.-May 1936
Crawford, Fred L., 1888-1957.
June and August 1936
Dempsey, Jack, 1895-1983.
April 1935
Ferguson, Homer, 1889-1982.
April 1935
Fitzgerald, Frank Dwight, 1885-1939.
1935-1936
Guest, Edgar A. (Edgar Albert), 1881-1959.
Feb. 1936; April 1936
Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.
1935
Lawrence, Howard Cyrus, 1890-1961.
1925; 1935-1936
Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.
Mar. 1936
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
Feb. 4, 1936; Apr. 9, 1936
Musselwhite, Harry Webster, 1868-1955.
Apr. and Sept. 1935
Osborn, Chase Salmon, b. 1860.
Jan. 1927; Dec. 1928; 1934-1936
Pollock, James Kerr, 1898-
1935-1936
Potter, William W., 1869-1940.
1934-1936
Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
1935-1936
Van Wagoner, Murray Delos, 1898-
Aug. 1, 1936
Yost, Fielding Harris, 1871-1946.
Oct.-Nov. 1935; June 1936